

Daniel Essel

Date of birth: 23/12/1991 | **Nationality:** Ghanaian | **Gender:** Male |

Phone number: (+233) 0542480731 (Mobile) | Email address:

dessel731@outlook.com | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-essel-4b784 |

Whatsapp Messenger: +233542480731

Address: Post Office Box 559, Agona Swedru, 00233, Central Region, Ghana (Home)

ABOUT ME

I am a professional teacher (technical), technologist, and IT expert with over four years of experience across diverse work fields. Throughout my career, I have honed my expertise in teaching, machining, and computer repair, seeking out challenging opportunities that allow me to make a meaningful impact on individuals' lives. I am driven by my passion to not only apply my knowledge, skills, and abilities but also to continuously enhance them in order to positively impact as many lives as I can.

WORK EXPERIENCE

14/04/2019 - 26/09/2020 Accra, Ghana

MOBILE REGISTRATION WORKSTATION OPERATOR NATIONAL IDENTIFICATIONN AUTHORITY

- -Input demographics and capturing of biometrics of applicants.
- -Identified, corrected (within my reach) and reported data entry errors as well as faulty peripherals.
- -Adhered to strict data confidentiality policies to prevent information leakage.
- -Most at times assist Supervising Registration Officer (SRO) to communicate with and educated applicants prior to every day's registration exercise, to help facilitate the registration exercise.

18/09/2017 – 23/07/2018 Mankessim, Central Region, Ghana

TECHNICAL TEACHER MANKESSIM SENIOR HIGH TECHNICAL SCHOOL

- -Taught theory and delivered practical instruction on basic engineering drawings.
- -Developed lesson plans to teach course materials according to schedule.
- -Planned, prepared and delivered instructional activities related to various art mediums.
- -Manage students and classroom and assist in extracurricular activities.
- -Encouraged student creativity with motivation, positive feedback and constructive criticism

17/09/2016 - 18/12/2016 Awutu Obrachire, Central Region, Ghana

TECHNICAL TEACHER OBRACHIRE SENIOR HIGH TECHNICAL SCHOOL

- -Taught theory and delivered practical instruction on basic metalworks.
- -Developed lesson plans to teach course materials according to schedule.
- -Planned, prepared and delivered instructional activities related to various art mediums.
- -Manage students and classroom and assist in extracurricular activities.
- -Encouraged student creativity with motivation, positive feedback and constructive criticism

09/04/2016 - 14/08/2016 Kasoa, Central Region, Ghana

MACHINIST DELIVERANCE MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

- -Operated machines like the lathe, drilling machine and welding machine to perform some machine operations such as drilling holes, facing off, turning and welding metal joints respectively.
- -Observed strict safety measures when working with equipment and machines to minimize accidents.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

22/08/2013 - 17/07/2017 Winneba, Central Region, Ghana

BSC. MECHANICAL TECHNOLOGY EDUCATION University of Educaton, Winneba

Website https://www.uew.edu.gh/

18/08/2012 - 10/05/2013 Awutu Bawjiase, Ghana

DIPLOMA COMPUTER HARDWARE AND SOFTWARE Hand of Grace Multimedia and IT College

04/09/2012 - 29/09/2013 Awutu Obrachire, Central Region, Ghana

WEST AFRICAN SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION (W.A.S.S.C.E.) Obrachire Senior High Technical School

15/09/2006 - 04/07/2008 Awutu Bawiiase, Central Region, Ghana

BASIC EDUCATION CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION (B.E.C.E.) Bawjiase District Assemble Junior High School

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **AKAN (FANTE)**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Computer literacy(Microsoft Word,Excel,Office,Powerpoint,Outlook,Adobe Photoshop) | Digital Literacy | Installation of computer components, servicing of computer hardware, computer peripherals | Operating System Installation | Quick typing experience on the keyboard | Digital communications | Basic knowledge of Al

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

HONOURS AND AWARDS

15/10/2015

Certificate of Appreciation – University of Education, Winneba- College of Technology Education, Kumasi I was awarded this certificate after successfully serving as the President of Mechanical Student Association (MECHSA) for two years (2015/2016 academic year) and achieving remarkable accomplishments during my tenure.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Music

Wildlife and Nature

Internet browsing

Reading

Writing

REFERENCE

Mr. Matthew Awuttey

Supervising Registration Officer (SRO), National Identification Authority

Email: awuteymattjunior@gmail.com

Phone: 0242839126

Mr. Enock Kwame Mensah

Teaching Mentor, Mankessim Senior High Technical School

Email: enochmensah1984@gmail.com

Phone: 0249466477

Mrs. Martha Danso

Former- Head of Department (Mechanical), University of Education, Winneba- College of Technology

Education

Phone: 0244220744

Mr. Francis Baah

C.E.O., Hand of Grace Multimedia and IT College

Email: francisbaah974@gmail.com

Phone: 0249323980